<?xml version="1.0"?>
<book>
    <page>
        <text x="92" y="-13" bold="true">Introduction</text>
        <text>Sea Magic involves, the crafting, working, and enchanting of jewelry. There are various enchants that are unique to jewelry. In here you can find instructions on how to craft the jewelry and how to enchant it as well as information on the various different enchantments that your pieces can have.

There are two ways in which to put this jewelry on, you can either craft yourself a Mirror or press the Enchant key. 
(V by Default).
        
There however is only one way to take it off, you will need to use the mirror to do so.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="22" y="-13" bold="true">Basic Mirror</text>
        <text>The basic mirror can be used to put on/take off your jewelry. It also acts like portable enchanting, but only allowing you to enchant at level 1, 3 or 5. It has 100 uses. Right click to open the interface. Mirrors are better when enchanting pearls vs an enchantment table.</text>
        <crafting x="15" y="15" size="2">
            <craft1>|ingotAluminum|ingotAluminum</craft1>
            <craft2>ingotAluminum|glass_pane|ingotAluminum</craft2>
            <craft3>ingotIron|ingotAluminum|</craft3>
            <craftResult>mirror.basic</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="82" y="-13" bold="true">Magic Mirror</text>
        <text>The Magic Mirror is one step up from the Basic Mirror. As it uses an enchanting table and 3 storage bookshelves to craft it, it allows you access to the full 30 levels of Portable Enchanting. On crafting, The Magic Mirror is set to Enchant from level 1-3. Shift-Right Clicking the Magic Mirror will cause the levels to increase by 3 each time. So after the first click it will enchant from level 4-6. This continues up to level 30. At this point shift right clicking will set the mirror back to levels 1-3.</text>
        <text y="108" bold="true">Celestial Mirror</text>
        <text y="144">The ever so magnificent Celestial Mirror, allows you to enchant from level 30-60. It works in the same way as the Magic Mirror. Some Enchantments need you to enchant at higher levels in order for them to be obtainable.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
        <crafting x="5">
            <craft1>minecraft:bookshelf|plankWood|minecraft:bookshelf</craft1>
            <craft2>plankWood|chest|plankWood</craft2>
            <craft3>minecraft:bookshelf|minecraft:bookshelf|minecraft:bookshelf</craft3>
            <craftResult>bookshelf</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="100" size="1">
            <craft1>pearl|mirror.basic|pearl</craft1>
            <craft2>bookshelf|enchanting_table|bookshelf</craft2>
            <craft3>pearl|bookshelf|pearl</craft3>
            <craftResult>mirror.magic</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="15" y="15" size="2">
            <craft1>dropletMagic|nether_star|dropletMagic</craft1>
            <craft2>bookshelf|mirror.magic|bookshelf</craft2>
            <craft3>goldenThread|bookshelf|goldenThread</craft3>
            <craftResult>mirror.celestial</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="102" y="-13" bold="true">Jewelry</text>
        <text>There are three types of jewelry that you can equip, rings, bracelets and necklaces. Each type has increasing durability as well as being able to hold more enchantments. Jewelry is made up of two components pearls and a binding.
        
        
        
Different colours of pearls affect various different things when creating jewelry, these are:

• Durability
• Max Level an Enchantment can be
• Max Enchantments on a piece of jewelry
• Bias towards an enchantment, in a mirror
• Special effect with Elemental Affinity
• Repair Cost
• Creation Cost</text>
    </page>
    <page>
    <text>The binding I talk of is different depending on the piece of jewelry you are making:
• Ring - Iron or Gold
• Bracelet - String or Golden Silk
• Necklace - Wool or Golden Thread

The binding is what holds your piece of jewelry together. It is what determines how 'strong willed' it is. When attempting to place an enchanted pearl on to a piece of jewelry. There is a chance of success. This chance is much greater, and therefore the chance of loss is less, when using a better quality of binding.

Bindings also have an effect on:
• Durability
• Creation Cost
• Max Enchantments on a piece of jewelry</text>
    </page>
    <page>
    <text x="82" y="-13" bold="true">Creation</text>
    <text x="0" y="78" bold="true">Repair</text>
    <text>Jewelry is not simply crafted, it must be crafted and then worked. You will need a Blacksmith's Hammer and Anvil. First you craft the item, then you must place it on a Blacksmith's Anvil. Then proceed to work it, until it is ready for use. The pearl and binding you use, both will affect the cost of creation. The cost does not directly correlate with durability.
   


As with creation, the only way to repair a piece of jewelry is to take it to the Blacksmith's Anvil and whack it back in to life. As always this costs XP, but it costs twice as much as repairing any other item.</text>
</page>
    <page>
        <text>Below is some examples of crafting jewelry. Replace the pearls with any other colour.</text>
        <crafting x="15" y="40" size="0.8">
            <craft1>ingotIron|pearlBlue|ingotIron</craft1>
            <craft2>ingotIron||ingotIron</craft2>
            <craft3>ingotIron|ingotIron|ingotIron</craft3>
            <craftResult>Mariculture:ring 0 {binding:"basic",material:"pearlBlue",}</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="90" y="40" size="0.8">
            <craft1>ingotGold|pearlRed|ingotGold</craft1>
            <craft2>ingotGold||ingotGold</craft2>
            <craft3>ingotGold|ingotGold|ingotGold</craft3>
            <craftResult>Mariculture:ring 0 {binding:"gold",material:"pearlRed",}</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="15" y="110" size="0.8">
            <craft1>string||string</craft1>
            <craft2>pearlOrange||pearlOrange</craft2>
            <craft3>|pearlOrange|</craft3>
            <craftResult>Mariculture:bracelet 0 {binding:"basic",material:"pearlOrange",}</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="90" y="110" size="0.8">
            <craft1>goldenSilk||goldenSilk</craft1>
            <craft2>pearlBlack||pearlBlack</craft2>
            <craft3>|pearlBlack|</craft3>
            <craftResult>Mariculture:bracelet 0 {binding:"gold",material:"pearlBlack",}</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="15" y="180" size="0.8">
            <craft1>pearlPurple|wool|pearlPurple</craft1>
            <craft2>pearlPurple||pearlPurple</craft2>
            <craft3>pearlPurple|pearlPurple|pearlPurple</craft3>
            <craftResult>Mariculture:necklace 0 {binding:"basic",material:"pearlPurple",}</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="90" y="180" size="0.8">
            <craft1>pearlWhite|goldenThread|pearlWhite</craft1>
            <craft2>pearlWhite||pearlWhite</craft2>
            <craft3>pearlWhite|pearlWhite|pearlWhite</craft3>
            <craftResult>Mariculture:necklace 0 {binding:"basic",material:"pearlWhite",}</craftResult>
            <craftNum>1</craftNum>
        </crafting>
    </page>
     <page>
        <text x="82" y="-13" bold="true">Enchanting</text>
        <text>While you are able to enchant jewelry directly in an enchantment table, this is not the best option as you will generally only get one enchantment on to your piece that way. So instead you should enchant pearls directly. It is recommended you enchant them inside of a mirror, as they will then have a bias to a specific enchantment, helping you out.
        
With your enchanted pearls, you can place them in a crafting grid with your piece of jewelry. (The colours must match). You must then take your jewelry to a Blacksmith's Anvil and work it for a short time. Once it's done, the enchantment that was on the pearl may make it's way on to the jewelry. Keep in mind, each jewelry type and pearl colour has limits on how many enchantments you can have, and the maximum level of these enchantments. Bindings are also important here as they increase the chance that an enchantment will stick instead of being lost entirely.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
    <text x="22" y="-13" bold="true">Enchantments</text>
    <text size="0.75" wrap="250">
    
Over the next few pages, you will find information on the various jewelry enchantments, what their max level is and descriptions on what they do.</text>
    <text bold="true" y="22" size="0.8">
    
    
    
Sonic the Hedgehog (MAX 5)
    
   
   
Leapfrog (MAX 4)




Step Up (MAX 3)




Fall Resistance (MAX 4)</text>
    <text y="63">Increases your speed when sprinting.</text>
    <hr y="62"></hr>
    <text y="95">Jump up 1 extra block per level when holding down the enchantment key.</text>
    <hr y="97"></hr>
    <text y="138">Walk up 1 extra block per level.</text>
    <hr y="133"></hr>
    <text y="180">Greater protection from fall damage dependant on the level enchanted to.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
    <text bold="true" y="-30" size="0.8">
    
    
    
Spiderman (MAX 1)
    
   
   
   
Paraglide (MAX 2)







Superman (MAX 3)





Reaper (MAX 3)</text>
    <text y="13">Allows you to climb walls, as long as it is toggled on. (Shift + Toggle Key)</text>
    <hr y="26"></hr>
    <text y="55">Paraglide has two modes, the second is only unlocked at level 2. The first mode is glide, which slows down your fall. The second is fast fall, which increases your fall. To switch modes use the Toggle Key.</text>
    <hr y="85"></hr>
    <text y="125">Grants the power of flight. Level increases the speed. Use the enchant key while airborne to change speed.</text>
    <hr y="128"></hr>
    <text y="175">Level 1: Items kept on death; Level 2: Respawn where you died; Level 3: Immunity after death</text>
    </page>
    <page>
    <text bold="true" y="-30" size="0.8">
    
    
    
Blink (MAX 3)
    
   
   
   
   
Restoration (MAX 3)






1 Up (MAX 3)





Never Hungry (MAX 5)</text>
    <text y="13">Enables Teleportation. Enchant key + right click on a block. Higher levels equals further distance.</text>
    <hr y="31"></hr>
    <text y="65" wrap="230">Repairs items at the cost of durability on jewelry. Level 1: Repairs held Item; Level 2: Repairs Hotbar; Level 3: Repairs Armour.</text>
    <hr y="85"></hr>
    <text y="125">If you die, you don't die. You will be revived instantly, and your health restored up to the level of this enchant.</text>
    <hr y="128"></hr>
    <text y="175">Restores your hunger bar. Level affects how much saturation is provided, therefore how long each feed lasts.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
    <text bold="true" y="-30" size="0.8">
    
    
    
Elemental Affinity (MAX 1)</text>
    <text>
    
This enchantment is entirely unique. The effect it has depends on the pearl that the jewelry is made from. Listed below are the effects:

• Black ~ Bonus attack damage at night
• Blue ~ Immune to drowning damage   
• Brown ~ Digging dirt provides Bait    
• Gold ~ Killing entities drop gold nuggets
• Green ~ Immunity to poison
• Orange ~ Bonus xp on kills
• Pink ~ Killing entities restores health
• Purple ~ Immune to magic damage
• Red ~ Immune to fire and lava
• Silver ~ Silverfish drop fishing loot
• White ~ Bonus attack damage at day
• Yellow ~ Immune to earthly damage  
    </text>
    </page>
</book>