<?xml version="1.0"?>
<book>
    <page>
        <text x="82" y="-13" bold="true">Materials</text>
        <text y="2" wrap="235" size="0.8">Mariculture introduces six basic 'raw' materials these are: Copper, Aluminium, Limestone, Rutile, Natural Gas and Pearls, there are also the secondary metals of Magnesium and Titanium, they are used in various different recipes within Mariculture.</text>
        <text y="39" bold="true">Copper</text>
        <text y="61">Copper is found like a normal ore and cooked in a furnace so go mining!</text>
        <text y="64" bold="true">Aluminium</text>
        <text y="91">Aluminium is found in the world as 'Bauxite', you must melt this down in a Crucible Furnace which will give you Molten Aluminium. You should then cool this to ingots.</text>
        <text y="113" bold="true">Limestone and Rutile</text>
        <text y="148">Limestone is generally found in watery biomes, nameley rivers and oceans, it generates quite commonly and only generates at the surface. Your best bet is to traverse the rivers of the world. Rutile will sometimes generate in place of a limestone piece.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text y="-12" bold="true">Natural Gas</text>
        <text y="0" wrap="222">Natural Gas is found in the depths of Ocean Biomes, the easiest way to locate it, is to swim around the ocean floor. You will come across some bubbles leaks. Digging down from these you will arrive in an air pocket, that gives you weakness and mining fatigue, whatever you do, do not set off a fire at this point! In order to collect the gas, you will need to power, or right click an Air Pump. This Air Pump will suck the gas in to a fluid, and will automatically eject it to any adjacent tanks.</text>
        <img mod="mariculture" src="processing/oyster" x="5" y="800" size="0.15" stretch="4.5"></img>
        <text y="135" bold="true">Oysters</text>
        <text y="174" wrap="222">Oysters are found at the bottom of the oceans. When supplied with a block of sand, they will generate Pearls overtime. The easiest way to collect them is to break the block underneath of them.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="92" y="-13" bold="true">Magnesium</text>
        <text>Magnesium is required to make Titanium which is used in some of the more advanced recipes. To obtain Magnesium you need to mix quicklime(molten limestone) with water. This will create a random dust, which you should melt in a crucible furnace. (Not all the water is used). This will most likely give you Molten Magnesium but if you have mods that add cobalt or nickel, you may get these instead.</text>
        <vat x="20" y="90" size="1.1">
            <fluid1 vol="3000">water</fluid1>
            <fluid2 vol="4000">quicklime</fluid2>
            <fluid3 vol="2000">water</fluid3>
            <output>Mariculture:materials 13</output>
            <time>10</time>
        </vat>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="32" y="-13" bold="true">Titanium</text>
        <text>Titanium is made by combining Magnesium and Rutile, you must combine them in a vat. 1 Magnesium and 1 Rutile will give you 1 Titanium.</text>
        <vat x="20" y="45" size="1.1">
            <fluid1 type=" ingot" vol="1">magnesium.molten</fluid1>
            <fluid2 type=" ingot" vol="1">rutile.molten</fluid2>
            <fluid3 type=" ingot" vol="1">titanium.molten</fluid3>
            <time>6</time>
        </vat>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="92" y="-13" bold="true">Processing</text>
        <text y="3" size="0.8" wrap="225">There are a few different blocks that you are going to need in order to craft various different things throughout Mariculture. In order to get started however, the first thing you will need to make is a Vat. This will allow you to make burnt bricks, which is what is needed to craft the other components for ore processing, crafting or otherwise. Vats can be two sizes, either simply a block on it's own or a 2x2 square of them. The larger size allows for recipes that require more fluid. The single Vat can only store 6000mB while the large can store 30000mB.</text>
        <crafting x="40" y="67" size="1.3">
            <craft1>ingotCopper||ingotCopper</craft1>
            <craft2>ingotCopper||ingotCopper</craft2>
            <craft3>ingotCopper|ingotCopper|ingotCopper</craft3>
            <craftResult>vat</craftResult>
        </crafting>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="32" y="-13" bold="true">Burnt Bricks</text>
        <text>Burnt Bricks are made in a Vat, there are two recipes to create them, one that uses normal bricks and the other using netherbricks.</text>
        <vat x="15" y="25" size="1.1">
            <input>brick</input>
            <fluid1 vol="500">lava</fluid1>
            <output>burntBrick</output>
            <time>16</time>
        </vat>
        <vat x="15" y="90" size="1.1">
            <input>netherbrick</input>
            <fluid1 vol="250">lava</fluid1>
            <output>burntBrick</output>
            <time>8</time>
        </vat>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="82" y="-13" bold="true">Crucible Furnace</text>
        <text>The Crucible Furnace can be used to help double up your ores. It's a two block structure constructed by placing one on top of another. Crucible Furnaces will melt your ores and other items down in to molten form, these molten metals can then be moved in to an Ingot Caster, where they will cool in to ingots. </text>
        <text y="76">The Furnace needs to be heated up first to specific temperatures depending on what you want to melt, it will accept solid or liquid fuels, and works better in certain biomes. The solid fuels that it accepts are sticks, planks, logs, coal, charcoal and coal blocks. It will accept Lava or Natural Gas as liquid fuels. In order to get it to use liquid fuels, you will need to place a tank underneath it. It will pull the liquids from within the tank and burn them up.</text>
        <text y="184" italic="true">(Furnaces also will accept Coal Coke, Fuel, Oil, Pyrotheum or Liquifacted Coal if the relevant mods/fluids exist)</text>
    </page>
    <page>
        <img mod="mariculture" src="processing/crucible" x="0" y="0" size="0.755" stretch="0.5"></img>
        <crafting x="100" y="-8" size="1">
            <craft1>|lava_bucket|</craft1>
            <craft2>burntBrick|normalTank|burntBrick</craft2>
            <craft3>heater|baseBrick|heater</craft3>
            <craftResult>crucible</craftResult>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="100" y="55" size="1">
            <craft1>burntBrick|iron_bars|burntBrick</craft1>
            <craft2>iron_bars||iron_bars</craft2>
            <craft3>burntBrick|iron_bars|burntBrick</craft3>
            <craftResult>baseBrick</craftResult>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="100" y="118" size="1">
            <craft1>ingotCopper|plankWood|ingotCopper</craft1>
            <craft2>plankWood|glass|plankWood</craft2>
            <craft3>ingotCopper|plankWood|ingotCopper</craft3>
            <craftResult num="2">normalTank</craftResult>
        </crafting>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="82" y="-13" bold="true">Ingot Caster</text>
        <text wrap="225">The Ingot Caster simply takes molten metals, and casts them in to ingots. The Biome will affect the speed at which it cools, it can cool up to four ingots worth at a time.</text>
        <crafting x="5" y="28" size="1">
            <craft1>|ingotCopper|</craft1>
            <craft2>|ingotCopper|</craft2>
            <craft3>ingotCopper||</craft3>
            <craftResult>ladle</craftResult>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="95" y="28" size="1">
            <craft1>|burntBrick|</craft1>
            <craft2>burntBrick|burntBrick|burntBrick</craft2>
            <craft3>|burntBrick|</craft3>
            <craftResult>ingotCaster</craftResult>
        </crafting>
        <text y="88" bold="true">Ladle</text>
        <text y="120">The ladle can be used to move liquid from your Crucible Furnace to the Ingot Caster (if you do not wish to place the caster next to the furnace), simply shift + right click on the furnace and this will fill up the ladle, and you can then right click the Ingot Caster to fill it. Ladles will work with any tank, allowing you to fill or drain them on the go. However they do only store 144mB worth of liquid.</text>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="10" y="-13" bold="true">Heat Resistant Bottles</text>
        <text y="2" wrap="235" size="0.8">Heat Resistant Bottles can also be used to transfer the liquids. These need to be placed inside of the Crucible Furnace first, in the fluid input slot, then they will pick up the fluid, you can then right click the caster to empty the bottles contents in. These bottles are crafted like normal bottles but are made with heat resistant glass and need to be filled with 2 ingots worth of molten metal. Heat Resistant glass is made with a Glass Block, Molten Aluminium and Quicklime (Melted Limestone).</text>
        <vat x="20" y="90" size="1.05">
            <input>glass</input>
            <fluid1 type="nugget" vol="1">aluminum.molten</fluid1>
            <fluid2 vol="900">quicklime</fluid2>
            <output>heatglass</output>
            <time>15</time>
        </vat>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="92" y="-13" bold="true">Void Bottle</text>
        <text wrap="221">The Void Bottle can be used like the other bottles in all Mariculture machines, however it's function is that it will completely drain all fluids contained in those machines. Void Bottles can also be placed in the world, and will act like a void tank, you can use them in conjunction with a ladle to help empty other mods machines. Just right click on their tanks (on the sides you can drain from), and then placed the fluids in the void tank, destroying them. Or store them somewhere if you like instead! (The recipe is shapeless)</text>
        <crafting x="42" y="77" size="1.25">
            <craft1>bottleEmpty|redstone|</craft1>
            <craft2>dyeBlack||</craft2>
            <craft3>||</craft3>
            <craftResult num="8">bottleVoid</craftResult>
        </crafting>
    </page>
    <page>
        <text x="10" y="-13" bold="true">Blacksmith's Anvil</text>
        <text y="2" wrap="235" size="0.8">The Blacksmith's Anvil is used to crush, smash, work, or repair items. In order to operate it, you need to place an item that can be worked on to it with a right click. Then with a Blacksmith's Hammer, just keep hitting the block until you are done constructing whatever it is. The Blacksmith Anvil can also be used to repair items and is the only way to repair jewelry. Repairing costs a bit of XP but normally a bit less than in a Vanilla Anvil, but if you have an item that can take 1000 damage, you'll need to whack it 1000 times, so it does have it's drawbacks.</text>
        <crafting x="5" y="104" size="1">
            <craft1>burntBrick|burntBrick|</craft1>
            <craft2>|nether_brick|burntBrick</craft2>
            <craft3>nether_brick||</craft3>
            <craftResult>hammer</craftResult>
        </crafting>
        <crafting x="100" y="104" size="1">
            <craft1>baseBrick|baseBrick|baseBrick</craft1>
            <craft2>|nether_brick|</craft2>
            <craft3>burntBrick|burntBrick|burntBrick</craft3>
            <craftResult>anvil</craftResult>
        </crafting>
    </page>
</book>